Fedor Lisin

theo.lisin@gmail.com 995 (574) 019-368

It took me around two years to realise that I like programming in general and data science in particular. Since taking the Yandex classes, well-written, readable code has become my intention. My current focus is creating products that benefit or facilitate the lives of people, not just reviewers.

Github TheoLisin Telegram @TedFox LinkedIn theo-lisin

SKILLS

ML AND DATA SCIENCE	sklearn, PyTorch, statistics, linear algebra
PYTHON DEVELOPMENT	FastAPI, Pydantic, ORM, SQLAlchemy, ML frameworks
CI/CD	Docker, Docker Compose, Github Actions, Gitlab Pipelines
C/C++	
COMMON	VSC, Gitlab, Github, Reviewing, Linux

EXPERIENCE

Python Developer Mar 2023 - Present

Create a new app on the Supervisely platform and provide client tech help.

• App for tracking on video of points, polygons, and rectangles using linear interpolation and NN.

Junior Data Scientist Sep 2021 - Sep 2022

Developed different models from scratch for tabular data and time series, upgraded the current data infrastructure, supervised the students' self-study pet projects.

- Train delay investigation system: improving data infrastructure, time to create the final dataset was at least cut in half. (Catboost, SQL, ClickHouse)
- EEG motor imaginary classification: examining the primary methods for getting, classifying, and filtering EEG data, as well as developing experimental data collection methods. (ICA, SSP, WPD)
- Recommendation system for ticket sales (students project): aided students in using their repository and fixed django framework issues. (Git, Conda, Django)

EDUCATION

St. Petersburg Academic University of RAS

Jan 2016 - Jan 2020

Bachelor - Theoretical Physics

MADE Data Academy

Jan 2022 - Jan 2023

- Data Science, MLOps

LANGUAGES

English

Intermediate

Russian

Native Speaker

INTERESTS

Games

Airplanes

• PPL

Traveling